# SHAHAB HUSSAIN

#### **Assistant Manager Human Resource**

Karachi job.shahab@gmail.com 0336-1133003

A Human Resources Graduate experienced in Training & Development, Human Capital Management, Recruitment, Employee Relations and business negotiations for logistics, industrial catering, corporate catering & engineering organizations. As a growing HR professional, I strive to achieve the highest levels of service, performance and professionalism to best represent the organization. I have an optimistic 'can-do' attitude in any given circumstances, and pride myself on being an optimistic and hardworking individual.

A smart professional with excellent communication, presentation, interpersonal & Leadership skills. People know me as a highly creative and friendly associate who can always be trusted to represent the company in a welcoming and professional manner.

Have facilitate our 700 learners in my training workshops. Have honor to design & develop paperless and minimum resource T&D information management system. Serving organization as Human Resource Business Partner. Willing to relocate: Anywhere

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Assistant Manager Human Resource**

S. Zia ul Haq & Sons Pvt. Ltd - Karachi

March 2016 to March 2020

- Administering various human resource plans and procedures for all organization personnel. Participating in developing department goals, objectives and systems, employee handbook, policies and procedures manual.
- · Liaise with functional or operational area managers to develop and implement local human resource strategy.
- Administering the compensation program; monitors the performance evaluation program and revises as necessary (Only temporary or contractual employment)
- Administering employee record; this include joining letter, employment contract, personal documents, leaves, absences, letters, employee entitlements, loans, bank letters, police verification, training certificate, promotion letter, etc.
- Liaising with internal audit and pay roll related matters.
- Administering final settlement, exit interview, loan applications, employee leaves & attendance, bank account opening process, experience letter, etc.
- Coordinating & supporting all recruitment activities including posting, internal & external recruitment portal management, job openings, candidate search, reviewing resumes and scheduling interviews. Mostly for temporary & contractual employment
- Design and implement Induction/Orientation programs for new joiners, employee counseling.
- Provide administrative support to the HR Manager in the creation and implementation of new policies, annual performance appraisal, new position review, employee termination, job rotation, performance feedback & reviews, training need analysis, revamping organizational HR policies and Organogram, inter office memorandum, etc.

- Participating in the conduct of investigations when employee complaints or concerns are brought forth
- Development of human resource management software including HRIS, T&D management and reporting system, manpower planning & rotation.
- Recommending new approaches, policies and procedures to continually improve efficiency of the department and services performed.
- Develop human resource reports; this includes employee turn out, leaves & absents, employee experience/expertise/ education level, working hours, performance reports, annual bonus recommendation, department objective compliance, etc.

# **Assistant Manager Operation Management**

S. Zia ul Haq & Sons Pvt. Ltd - Karachi

March 2015 to March 2016

- Ensure effective supervision and control over managing SZS services at rig sites according to the SOW.
- Ensure compliance of HSE, HACCP and ISO-Standards.
- Supervision and monitoring of RSD coordinator for unhindered provision of services at rig sites.
- Seeking and maintaining effective coordination between concerned dept.
- Supervised overall costing system, HR management, IT system and operation support.
- Supervised and coached camp managers on a daily basis.
- Prepared monthly activity report, fulfilled audit related requirement and generated year end reports.
- Supervised the maintenance of database/archive and administrative files.
- Administered employee payroll, benefits and insurance.

### **Senior Executive Operation Management**

S. Zia Ul Haq & Sons (Pvt.) Ltd - Karachi

January 2013 to February 2015

- Ensure effective supervision and control over managing SZS services at rig sites according to the SOW.
- Ensure compliance of HSE, HACCP and ISO-Standards.
- Supervision and monitoring of RSD coordinator for unhindered provision of services at rig sites.
- Seeking and maintaining effective coordination between concerned dept.
- Supervised overall costing system, HR management, IT system and business controls.
- Supervised and coached camp managers on a daily basis.
- Prepared monthly activity report, fulfilled audit related requirement and generated year end reports.
- Supervised the maintenance of database/archive and administrative files.
- Administered employee payroll, benefits and insurance

#### **Executive Operation Management**

S. Zia Ul Haq & Sons (Pvt.) Ltd - Karachi

January 2012 to December 2012

- Effective supervision and monitoring for SZS services at Rig sites, Power Plants, Guest houses and other client's facilities.
- Responsible for the proper compliance of HSE, HACCP and ISO-Standards at all operational levels.
- Leading team of Operational Coordinators for unhindered provision of services at remote locations.
- Responsible for budgeting, Menu standardization and other routine operational activities.

# **Coordinator Operation Management**

S. Zia Ul Haq & Sons (Pvt.) Ltd - Karachi

January 2011 to December 2011

• Controlling and monitoring to ensure timely & effective coordination between concerned departments and clients.

# **Camp Administrator**

Weatherford, Saxon rig sites and fields care of SZS (Pvt.)

July 2010 to December 2010

At Pakistan Petroleum Limited, Weatherford, Saxon rig sites and fields care of SZS (Pvt.) Ltd.

- Ensure SOW for Catering, Housekeeping, Maintenance and overall Camp Management at various rig sites of multinational organizations throughout Pakistan.
- Team Led Operations for staff management, motivation and training

#### **Front Officer Cashier**

Regent Plaza Hotel & Convention Center - Karachi

March 2009 to October 2010

- Operates front office posting software.
- Obtains the house bank and keeps it balanced.
- Completes cashier pre-shift supply checklist.
- · Completes guest check-in procedures.
- Clarifies customers question or concerns about the charges on their bills.
- Maintains adequate supplies of outlet stationery for cashiers.
- Assists with distribution of month end reports as directed by accounts or front office manager.
- · Attends meetings as required.
- · Maintains a track of all high balance guests.
- Check and follow up on all bills on hold.
- Check the billing instructions are correct for all expected departure guest and setup required auto routing or auto transfer on the PMS / Guest folio.
- Give on the Job training for new staffs.
- May also perform a variety of banking services for guests, Such as check cashing and foreign currency exchange.
- Follow up on all deposit dues / deposit to be paid.
- · Post charges to guest accounts.
- Handles paid-outs.
- Transfer guest balances to other accounts as required.
- · Cashes checks for guests following the approval policy.
- · Completes guest check-out procedures.
- · Settles guest accounts.
- Dispenses guest records after the guest checkout
- Handles cash, credit cards and direct billing requests properly.
- Posts non-guest ledger payments.
- · Makes discount adjustments.
- Disperses guest record upon check-out.
- Balances department totals at the close of the shift.
- Balances cash at the close of the shift.
- Manages safe deposit boxes.
- Assists Front desk staff on check in as an when required.

#### **Power Generation Internee**

**Nakshbandi Industries** - Karachi February 2008 to February 2009 To work in and learn various aspects of electric utility diesel & gas generator power plant maintenance engineering functions. Responsibilities include executing and completing significant assigned projects and day to day plant maintenance activities under the oversight and direction of the staff Maintenance Engineer and Maintenance Department.

#### **Accounts Assistant**

QFS International Transport - Karachi

August 2004 to April 2007

Manage bus station (UTS-3, 4, 9, 10) cash & accounts related matters

- Maintain and update general ledger and sales journal
- Obtain approval to payment of day to day expenses and maintenance of buses.
- Prepare, fulfill and distribute checks/cash
- Scan, file and log accounting documents
- · Deposit cash to bank
- · Day to day cash closing.

## **EDUCATION**

# Master's in Human Resource Management

**University of Karachi** - Karachi March 2012 to August 2014

## **Bachelor's in Commerce**

University of Karachi - Karachi

March 2008 to July 2011

## **Intermediate in Commerce**

Sindh Board of Intermediate - Karachi

March 2005 to August 2007

# **High School in Science**

Kulsoom Bai Valika C.A.A Model School & College - Karachi

March 2000 to March 2002

# **SKILLS**

- Training Need Analysis (3 years)
- Design Policies & SOP's (2 years)
- Employee Relation (5 years)
- Training & Presentation (3 years)
- Reporting & Analysis (5 years)

- Performance Management (4 years)
- Data Analysis (3 years)
- Human Capital Management (4 years)
- Learning & Development (3 years)
- Payroll Management (3 years)
- Recruitment & Selection (3 years)
- Power BI (1 year)

# **LINKS**

http://www.linkedin.com/in/shahab-hussain-83545a55

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES**

## **Microsoft Excel Advance**

July 2017 to July 2017

# **Payroll Management & Preparation**

June 2016 to June 2016

# **Personnel Management & Performance Appraisal**

April 2016 to April 2016

## **Productive Improvement via Lean Manufacturing**

March 2014 to March 2014

## **Food Safety Training from Traincan Canada**

January 2020 to January 2020

# Modern Human Resource Management - Training and Induction - Revised

June 2019 to July 2019

Modern Human Resource Management Training and Induction - Revised https://alison.com/certification/c heck/ %242y%2410%24duOJ3DhL2 IA1s8f11sWQAOw7DTeF9cK.gek5 RIzaGIfvDd5g

# **Diploma in Human Resources Revised 2017**

October 2019 to November 2019

Diploma in Human Resources Revised 2017 https://alison.com/certification/c heck/%242y%2410%24FbyqtHgRn 5G6uL8TDKnBoOgUCqfM22q9KqL ziOHoiZOYADrY

# Prep: SHRM-CP

May 2020 to May 2020

Certificate Id: AX5Xs1Jhc2tFVgLcta2J4NmyZaJk

# Professional in Human Resources (PHR)®

April 2020 to April 2020

Certificate Id: ARkh4qVnR07A8eD-3RtzKgLWhpJQ

### HR as a Business Partner

May 2020 to May 2020

Certificate Id: Ad0ONfImBIGrUaE3YyFDxnyMh0h9

#### **Human Resources Foundations**

May 2020 to May 2020

Program: Society for Human Resource Management (SHRM®) | Registry ID: #RP4455

Certificate No: AcUw9NyNUCfrz275QalXwOnQyJG6

SHRM-CP® and SHRM-SCP® are trademarks of the Society

# **Organization Design**

May 2020 to May 2020

Program: PMI® Registered Education Provider | Provider ID: #4101

Certificate No: AZZvS4scS9-uhfLkqGVtK2RqQMi0

## **Learning Data Analytics**

May 2020 to May 2020

Field of Study: Information Technology

Program: National Association of State Boards of Accountancy (NASBA) | Registry ID: #140940

Certificate No: AWe\_-rYBrVaZrACk1cOGgYp2SyN8

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Projects Completed in Assistant Manager Role

Training & Development Management and Reporting System http://202.61.34.222/tm/ Consulting for designing of ERP based T&D system for the group of companies managing employee training record, TNA and its compliance, training nominations, employee records, training assessments, training feedbacks, Dashboard view for Management, etc.

#### **Employee Portal**

Designing of Employee Portfolio integrated with HRIS and Training & Development plans for 21 trades of employees. Support to well present experienced & trained work forced to client and internal business units.

#### Job Evaluation - Engineering Division

Job Evaluation of 317 employees, Trade base employee grading structure and succession plan, Re-Designing of employees Job Descriptions and Training Matrix.

#### Training Need Assessment and Performance Evaluation

Designed online TNA and Performance Appraisal for employee and HOD's.

#### **Reduce Cost of Training Operation**

Design T&D Management & Reporting System for in-house and remote users. Improve information effectiveness, easy to access, reduced time of reporting and rework, almost paper less management.

## **Training Material**

Developed new in-house training presentations, tests, training manuals, pocket guides, learning flyers / posters etc. in Urdu and in English languages.

#### Training & Development Module

http://202.61.34.222/tm/

Design training & development module for ZIA group of companies, managing +2000 temporary employment, +1200 permanent employment training needs & records. Basic training categories are "On Job Training, In-House Training, Management Development Program, etc.